optify.net 2012-12-28

# Optfiy's Privacy Policy | Optify

Optify, Inc. is committed to respecting your privacy. This privacy policy describes the measures we take to protect your privacy in connection with your use of [www.optify.net](http://www.optify.net/) (the “Site”).

This Privacy Policy applies to both corporate and individual customers and the individual users of our services. Customers and users are collectively referred to herein as “you.”

### TRUSTe

[](https://privacy-policy.truste.com/click-with-confidence/wps/en/www.optify.net/seal_m "TRUSTe online privacy certification")Optify has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe’s program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe’s mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [support@optify.net](mailto:support@optify.net). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). The TRUSTe program applies only to information collected prior to the login feature of this website, except for the purpose of completing a transaction.

### What Information We Collect

**Registration.** If you choose to register with the Site, we may ask for your name, title, company name, billing address, e-mail address, phone number and other relevant information. When you create an account, we require that you create a user name and password.

**Feedback and Optify Support.** We use a third party service provider to host our feedback and Optify Support pages. You may submit contact information, such as your name, address, telephone number, or email address, in connection with feedback, concerns, complaints, questions, or technical support. Such information is used only to respond to those inquiries and is governed by this Privacy Policy.

**IP Address.** An Internet Protocol (“IP”) address is a unique string of numbers that is assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider. Web servers automatically identify your computer by its IP address. We will use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, to log your visits and to administer our Site. Your IP address also may be used to gather broad demographic information.

**Cookies.** A “cookie” is a small data file that can be placed on your hard drive when you visit certain websites. We may use cookies supplied by your browser or by third-party add-ins. We use session identification cookies to collect, store and sometimes track information for statistical purposes to improve the services we provide. We also use a persistent cookie to save your settings and to provide customizable and personalized services (including, without limitation to hold your shopping cart information). We do not tie any Personal Information to the cookies that we set on our Site.

A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. There are two instances in which we use a permanent cookie. First, when you visit our Site and request documentation or a response from us. Second, when you “Sign Up” or “Sign In” to our service. We send a permanent cookie to your browser when you have filled out the information on the “Sign Up” form or when you “Sign In” to our service.

These cookies do not enable third parties to access any of your personally identifiable information. Additionally, be aware that if you visit other websites you may be required to accept cookies. Advertisers and partners may also use their own cookies on our Site. We do not control use of these cookies and expressly disclaim responsibility for information collected through them.

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs/Pixel Tags).** Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are placed on a user’s hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on webpages. We may use clear gifs to track information for statistical purposes to improve the services we provide. Our use of clear gifs will not enable third parties to access any of your personally identifiable information. Additionally, be aware that advertisers and partners may also use their own clear gifs. We do not control use of these and expressly disclaim responsibility for information collected through them.

**Order Processing** If you purchase services from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and address) and financial information (such as credit card number, card verification value (CVV), and expiration date). We will share this information with our third party credit card processor for billing purposes and to fill your orders. This company is authorized to use your information only as necessary to provide this service to us. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you. This information is also used to send you updates on the product or service you purchased.

Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use Flash cookies to collect and store information.

Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored. Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118>

**Log data.** We automatically collect typical web server log data (such as IP addresses and the pages you visit) when you use the Site. This information helps us evaluate how our subscribers use the services.

**User Content.** You may elect to contribute content to the Site including forum postings, blog entries, and other content that you own or have the right to display and reproduce. Providing such information is optional. Please note that any personally identifiable information you post these forums, blog entries, or other content to our Site may be viewed by others and used by others to send you unsolicited messages. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [support@optify.net](mailto:support@optify.net). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Add New User Feature.** Users designated with “Admin” rights have the ability to use the “Add New User” feature which includes submission of a name, email address and Twitter signature. We collect this information and generate an email invitation to confirm such party’s acceptance of such use, including the forming of a customer relationship, and to create a unique password. Both the Admin and Optify have the ability to track a new user’s login, profile and usage.

**Customer Testimonials.** We post customer testimonials on our Site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer’s consent via email to include their name prior to posting the testimonial.

### How We Use Personally Identifiable Information

**Customer Relationship.** We will use your personally identifiable information in the context of your customer relationship with Optify, including setting up your account, the operation of our Site, solving problems associated with our Site and services, improving our Site and services, reporting, and providing you with our newsletters. From time-to-time we notify our customers of new products or services that will better meet their needs, announcements, updates and upgrades. If you would like to opt-out of being notified, please contact us at the address given at the end of this Privacy Policy. If you would like to change your preferences online, please contact us at [support@optify.net](mailto:support@optify.net). If you receive a marketing communication from our subsidiaries, business partners or independent resellers, you should opt-out with that entity directly. Please be aware that we will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

**Targeted Information.** We may associate your personally identifiable information with your viewing history, comments and/or other non-personally identifiable information we collect from you while you are on our Site for our internal purposes. We will not share this information with third parties without your permission, although we may provide data to third parties in an anonymized form that cannot be used to identify you as an individual.

Optify partners with Salesforce.com to organize requests for sales related contacts. If you request more information about our services we send your contact and other information to our account at SalesForce.com. Salesforce.com is an application service provider that many companies use to organize prospects and call-back requests, etc. They are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose. Salesforce.com participates in the TRUSTe Privacy Seal program.

**Credentials.** When you first sign up for a service with Optify, we use your registration information to assign credentials to you. These credentials permit you to access the services and use certain administrative features.

**Email.** From time to time, we may send e-mail messages informing you of products and services we believe may be of interest to you. Those marketing e-mails may contain code that enables our database to track the usage of the e-mails, including whether the e-mail was opened and/or what links (if any) were clicked. We will combine such information to improve your experience with our services and equipment and/or provide customized e-mail communications.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at support@optify.net. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### How We Share Information

Except as set forth below, we will not share, sell, rent, or trade your personally identifiable information with third parties (aside from entities that perform services for us that are either bound to comply with our Privacy Policy or have privacy policies that protect your information).

We may disclose information you provide if required to do so by law or if we have a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process served on us; (2) protect and defend our rights or property; (3) act in an emergency to protect someone’s safety; and/or (4) to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Site.

We may gather usage data and demographic information from you from time to time. We will not share such information with any person or entity in a manner that identifies you as an individual, unless we let you know that at the time of collection, or we have your permission. When we share usage and demographic information with third parties, we will give them aggregate information only.

As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets, and, depending upon the transaction, your personally identifiable information may be one of the transferred assets. In the event Optify is acquired, merges with another entity, becomes insolvent, and/or declares bankruptcy, your personal information may be transferred or sold to another entity, in accordance with applicable law. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

### Options to Control Use of Personally Identifiable Information

Although most users tell us they value receiving information about our services and partners, we recognize the importance of providing you with choice and control. You may also contact us by[ support@optify.net](mailto:support@optify.net). Please include your current contact information so that we can make the appropriate corrections. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days of receiving it.

### What Else You Should Know About Privacy

**Blogs.** If you use blogs, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected or used by other users of the Site, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these areas of the Site. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [support@optify.net](mailto:support@optify.net). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Security.** We have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. The personally identifiable information we collect about you is stored in limited access servers. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to maintain safeguards to protect the security of these servers and your personal information. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, Optify uses standard physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information Optify collects.

**Links to Other Sites.** Our Site may contain hyperlinks and pointers to websites maintained by third parties. These links are provided for your reference only. We do not control, operate or endorse in any respect information, products or services on such third-party websites and are not responsible for their content. Many third-party sites have their own privacy policies that differ from ours. This Privacy Policy only covers our Site and does not cover any other website. While we make every effort to keep your information secure, we do not control the policies of other websites.

**Twitter.** We allow you to import your Twitter account into Optify’s dashboard. When you click on the ‘Twitter for Business’ link you are then transferred to Twitter to sign into your account. Once you have signed into your Twitter account, Optify will import all of your Twitter posts allowing you to make posts directly on our Site. These posts will be posted on your Twitter page as well. We do not store your Twitter login or password for the purpose of allowing you to use your account while on Optify. We will not use this information for any other purpose.

Your Twitter posts as well as your Twitter page will be viewable by the public. If you do not wish to have your Twitter posts or page viewable by the public on our Site then please do not enable or use this feature. Please do not post any personal information within your posts on our Site as it is viewable by the public on our Site as well as Twitter and may be used to send you unsolicited messages.

**Google Analytics.** We use Google Analytics to track website visitor sources and on-site behavior. In addition, we use Google Analytics for Display Advertisers to identify visitors to optify.net in order to target specific browsers with advertising that is relevant only to Optify visitors and customers. You may opt out of this targeting by visiting the [Google Ads Preference Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/).

### AddThis Widget

We use the AddThis widget on our Site to allow users to share our blog posts with their friends from our Site, by allowing them to send a one time email within the widget, inviting their friend to visit the blog. We do not have access to any of the personal information collected within this widget. We also use the AddThis widget to allow users to log into their third party social networking accounts and share a link to bedbug.com with their friends. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

### Add your Competitors

**Add your Competitors.** We use the “Add your Competitors” feature on our Site to allow users to develop strategies and gain traffic to their URL that may be going to a competitor. By adding general competitor information, our service allows users to (i) tracks a competitor’s website(s) rank in search engines across targeted keywords, (ii) gain insight into competitor’s achievements or (iii) highlight your achievements compared to that of a competitor. We also collect the name of the competitor and associated URL in order to improve the service we offer to users.

### Optify’s Software as a Service (SaaS) Privacy Policy

The following information discloses how information is submitted via our applications and how we handle the information for our clients who are the owners of this data.

We provide our customers with applications that enable businesses to drive more traffic and leads with SEO and social media, convert visitors to customers, and measure and share results. These applications are not a part of our corporate web site. We serve our customers who use these applications. More specifically, we do not own the information that is submitted to our applications. The information that is submitted to our applications will be subject to our customers’ privacy policies.

**Optify Employees.** Optify’s employees are required to keep user information private as a condition of their employment. Only selected, authorized employees are permitted to access your personal information. All employees and contractors must abide by our Privacy Policy and company privacy rules.

**Children’s Personally Identifiable Information.** The Site is not directed to children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy.** If we decide to change our privacy policies, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the changes taking effect.

### Contacting Optify

We would like to receive your comments and questions about this Privacy Policy and any other matter you have regarding our services. Please address comments or questions to us via e-mail or postal mail.

You can e-mail us at: [support@optify.net](mailto:support@optify.net). You may also contact us by mail at:

Optify, Inc.  
Attention: Legal  
710 Second Avenue, Suite 840  
Seattle, WA 98104

### Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information

If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as your name, primary domain, Twitter account, or email address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users’ personally identifiable information.

Updating or correcting information can usually be done by logging onto [www.optify.net](http://www.optify.net/), clicking on Settings and then going to the “Edit” link; by contacting Customer Service [support@optify.net](mailto:support@optify.net), or by contacting us by postal mail at the contact information listed above. Deleting or deactivating an account can only be handled by contacting Customer Service at [support@optify.net](mailto:support@optify.net). Please specify “Privacy Statement” in the subject line of your e-mail. You may also call us at (206) 388-4232 or toll-free at 1-877-2-OPTIFY.

If you do not receive a reply from us or if you believe that your inquiry has not been satisfactorily resolved, please contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from this Web site.

### Acceptance of Privacy Policy

Your use of our Site, including any dispute concerning privacy, is subject to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use available at www.optify.net/legal. BY USING OUR SITE, YOU ARE ACCEPTING THE PRACTICES SET OUT IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the changes on this page. Please check the revision date at the bottom of this page to determine if the Privacy Policy has been modified since you last reviewed it. Your continued use of any portion of our Site following posting of the updated Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of the changes.

### Effective Date

This Privacy Policy was last revised on November 8, 2011.
